{
    "quizzes": [
        {
            "title": "CS/IT ENGINEERING",
            "icon": "./assets/images/icon-html.svg",
            "questions": [
                {
                    "question": "In a class, there are 60 students, out of which 30 are girls. What is the ratio of boys to girls in the class?",
                    "options": [
                        "2:1",
                        "1:2",
                        "1:1",
                        "3:2"
                    ],
                    "answer": "1:1"
                },
                {
                    "question": "A train travels 400 km in 5 hours. What is its average speed in km/hr?",
                    "options": [
                        "75 km/hr",
                        "80 km/hr",
                        "85 km/hr",
                        "90 km/hr"
                    ],
                    "answer": "80 km/hr"
                },
                {
                    "question": "If the cost price of 20 articles is equal to the selling price of 25 articles, what is the profit percentage?",
                    "options": [
                        "20%",
                        "25%",
                        "30%",
                        "35%"
                    ],
                    "answer": "30%"               
                },
                {
                    "question": "The perimeter of a rectangle is 40 cm and its length is twice its breadth. What is the area of the rectangle?",
                    "options": [
                         "a) 40 sq cm",
                         "b) 60 sq cm",
                         "c) 80 sq cm",
                         "d) 100 sq cm"
                    ],
                    "answer": "b) 60 sq cm"
                },
                {
                    "question": "If 15% of x is equal to 20% of y, and y = 200, what is the value of x?",
                    "options": [
                        "a) 150",
                        "b) 200",
                        "c) 250",
                        "d) 300"
                    ],
                    "answer": "a) 150"
                },
                {
                    "question": "A cube has a volume of 64 cubic meters. What is the length of its side?",
                    "options": [
                        "a) 4 meters",
                        "b) 6 meters",
                        "c) 8 meters",
                        "d) 10 meters"
                    ],
                    "answer": "b) 6 meters"
                },
                {
                    "question": "If the ratio of the circumference of two circles is 3:4, what is the ratio of their areas?",
                    "options": [
                        "a) 3:4",
                        "b) 9:16",
                        "c) 16:9",
                        "d) 27:64"
                    ],
                    "answer": "b) 9:16"
                },
                {
                    "question": "A bag contains 5 red balls and 7 green balls. If a ball is drawn at random, what is the probability of getting a green ball?",
                    "options": [
                        "a) 5/12",
                        "b) 7/12",
                        "c) 5/7",
                        "d) 7/5"
                    ],
                    "answer": "b) 7/12"
                },
                {
                    "question": "If the marked price of an article is Rs. 480 and after allowing a discount of 20%, it is sold for Rs. 384. What is the profit percentage?",
                    "options": [
                        "a) 20%",
                        "b) 25%",
                        "c) 30%",
                        "d) 35%"
                    ],
                    "answer": "c) 30%"
                },
                {
                    "question": "The sum of three consecutive odd numbers is 63. What is the largest of these numbers?",
                    "options": [
                        "a) 21",
                        "b) 23",
                        "c) 25",
                        "d) 27"
                    ],
                    "answer": "d) 27"
                },
                {
                    "question": "Statement: All cats are mammals. Conclusion: All mammals are cats. Is the conclusion true based on the statement?",
                    "options": [
                        "a) True",
                        "b) False",
                        "c) Cannot be determined"
                    ],
                    "answer": "b) False"
                },
                {
                    "question": "Arrange the given words in a meaningful sequence. River Ocean Sea Lake Choose the correct sequence:",
                    "options": [
                        "a) 1, 2, 3, 4",
                        "b) 2, 1, 3, 4",
                        "c) 2, 3, 1, 4",
                        "d) 3, 4, 1, 2"
                    ],
                    "answer": "c) 2, 3, 1, 4"
                },
                {
                    "question": "If TRAIN is coded as RTINA, how is CAUTION coded?",
                    "options": [
                        "a) UCATINO",
                        "b) UCNOTAI",
                        "c) UCOITNA",
                        "d) UCTIONA"
                    ],
                    "answer": "b) UCNOTAI"
                },
                {
                    "question": "If A = 1, B = 2, C = 3, ... Z = 26, then what is the value of HARD?",
                    "options": [
                        "a) 30",
                        "b) 28",
                        "c) 32",
                        "d) 34"
                    ],
                    "answer": "c) 32"
                },
                {
                    "question": "If the day after tomorrow is two days before Thursday, then what day is today?",
                    "options": [
                        "a) Monday",
                        "b) Tuesday",
                        "c) Wednesday",
                        "d) Thursday"
                    ],
                    "answer": "b) Tuesday"
                },
                {
                    "question": "If 5 + 3 = 28, 9 + 1 = 810, and 8 + 6 = 214, then 7 + 5 = ?",
                    "options": [
                        "a) 1112",
                        "b) 1230",
                        "c) 2121",
                        "d) 3124"
                    ],
                    "answer": "a) 1112"
                },
                {
                    "question": "If all roses are red and some red things are thorns, then:",
                    "options": [
                        "a) All roses are thorns.",
                        "b) Some roses are thorns.",
                        "c) Some thorns are roses.",
                        "d) None of the above."
                    ],
                    "answer": "b) Some roses are thorns."
                },
                {
                    "question": "If some stones are rocks and all rocks are mountains, then:",
                    "options": [
                        "a) All stones are mountains.",
                        "b) Some stones are mountains.",
                        "c) Some mountains are stones.",
                        "d) None of the above."
                    ],
                    "answer": "b) Some stones are mountains."
                },
                {
                    "question": "Find the odd one out:",
                    "options": [
                        "a) Square",
                        "b) Triangle",
                        "c) Circle",
                        "d) Rectangle"
                    ],
                    "answer": "c) Circle"
                },
                {
                    "question": "If the first two statements are true, is the last statement true? All players are winners. Some winners are champions. All players are champions.",
                    "options": [
                        "a) True",
                        "b) False",
                        "c) Cannot be determined"
                    ],
                    "answer": "a) True"
                },
                {
                    "question": "Which of the following Python functions correctly checks if a given string is a palindrome?",
                    "options": [
                        "a) def is_palindrome(s):\n    return s == s[::-1]",
                        "b) def check_palindrome(s):\n    return s == s.reverse()",
                        "c) def palindrome(s):\n    return s == s[::-1]",
                        "d) def check(s):\n    return s == s.reverse()"
                    ],
                    "answer": "a) def is_palindrome(s):\n    return s == s[::-1]"
                },
                {
                    "question": "Which of the following is a valid way to declare a variable in JavaScript?",
                    "options": [
                        "a) var 1variable = 10;",
                        "b) var variable#1 = 10;",
                        "c) var _variable = 10;",
                        "d) var variable-1 = 10;"
                    ],
                    "answer": "c) var _variable = 10;"
                },
                {
                    "question": "What is the time complexity of the QuickSort algorithm in the worst-case scenario?",
                    "options": [
                        "a) O(n)",
                        "b) O(n log n)",
                        "c) O(n^2)",
                        "d) O(log n)"
                    ],
                    "answer": "c) O(n^2)"
                },
                {
                    "question": "Which of the following is NOT a valid keyword in Java?",
                    "options": [
                        "a) transient",
                        "b) persistent",
                        "c) volatile",
                        "d) synchronized"
                    ],
                    "answer": "b) persistent"
                },
                {
                    "question": "What is the output of the following code snippet in Python? \n\nprint(10 // 3)",
                    "options": [
                        "a) 3.333",
                        "b) 3",
                        "c) 3.0",
                        "d) 3.33"
                    ],
                    "answer": "b) 3"
                },
                {

                    "question": "Which of the following Python functions correctly calculates the factorial of a given number?",
                    "options": [
                        "a) def fact(n):\n    if n == 0:\n        return 1\n    else:\n        return n * fact(n-1)",
                        "b) def calc_factorial(n):\n    return n * calc_factorial(n-1)",
                        "c) def find_factorial(n):\n    if n == 0:\n        return 1\n    else:\n        return n * find_factorial(n-1)",
                        "d) def factorial(n):\n    if n == 0:\n        return 1\n    else:\n        return n * factorial(n-2)"
                    ],
                    "answer": "c) def find_factorial(n):\n    if n == 0:\n        return 1\n    else:\n        return n * find_factorial(n-1)"
                },
                {
                    "question": "What is the time complexity of the Merge Sort algorithm in the worst-case scenario?",
                    "options": [
                        "a) O(n)",
                        "b) O(n log n)",
                        "c) O(n^2)",
                       "d) O(log n)"
                    ],
                    "answer": "b) O(n log n)"
                },
                {
                    "question": "Which of the following data structures does not use pointers?",
                    "options": [
                        "a) Linked List",
                        "b) Tree",
                        "c) Stack",
                        "d) Array"
                    ],
                    "answer": "d) Array"
                },
                {
                    "question": "Which of the following Python functions correctly finds the nth Fibonacci number recursively?",
                    "options": [
                        "a) def fib(n):\n    if n <= 1:\n        return n\n    else:\n        return fib(n-1) + fib(n-2)",
                        "b) def find_fibonacci(n):\n    if n <= 1:\n        return n\n    else:\n        return find_fibonacci(n-1) + find_fibonacci(n-2)",
                        "c) def calculate_fib(n):\n    if n <= 1:\n        return n\n    else:\n        return calculate_fib(n-1) + calculate_fib(n-2)",
                        "d) def get_fib(n):\n    if n <= 1:\n        return n\n    else:\n        return get_fib(n-1) + get_fib(n-2)"
                    ],
                    "answer": "a) def fib(n):\n    if n <= 1:\n        return n\n    else:\n        return fib(n-1) + fib(n-2)"
                }
            ]
        },
        {
            "title": "CIVIL ENGINEERING",
            "icon": "./assets/images/icon-css.svg",
            "questions": [
                {
                    "question": "In a class, there are 60 students, out of which 30 are girls. What is the ratio of boys to girls in the class?",
                    "options": [
                        "2:1",
                        "1:2",
                        "1:1",
                        "3:2"
                    ],
                    "answer": "1:1"
                },
                {
                    "question": "A train travels 400 km in 5 hours. What is its average speed in km/hr?",
                    "options": [
                        "75 km/hr",
                        "80 km/hr",
                        "85 km/hr",
                        "90 km/hr"
                    ],
                    "answer": "80 km/hr"
                },
                {
                    "question": "If the cost price of 20 articles is equal to the selling price of 25 articles, what is the profit percentage?",
                    "options": [
                        "20%",
                        "25%",
                        "30%",
                        "35%"
                    ],
                    "answer": "30%"
                },
                {
                    "question": "The perimeter of a rectangle is 40 cm and its length is twice its breadth. What is the area of the rectangle?",
                    "options": [
                         "a) 40 sq cm",
                         "b) 60 sq cm",
                         "c) 80 sq cm",
                         "d) 100 sq cm"
                    ],
                    "answer": "b) 60 sq cm"
                },
                {
                    "question": "If 15% of x is equal to 20% of y, and y = 200, what is the value of x?",
                    "options": [
                        "a) 150",
                        "b) 200",
                        "c) 250",
                        "d) 300"
                    ],
                    "answer": "a) 150"
                },
                {
                    "question": "A cube has a volume of 64 cubic meters. What is the length of its side?",
                    "options": [
                        "a) 4 meters",
                        "b) 6 meters",
                        "c) 8 meters",
                        "d) 10 meters"
                    ],
                    "answer": "b) 6 meters"
                },
                {
                    "question": "If the ratio of the circumference of two circles is 3:4, what is the ratio of their areas?",
                    "options": [
                        "a) 3:4",
                        "b) 9:16",
                        "c) 16:9",
                        "d) 27:64"
                    ],
                    "answer": "b) 9:16"
                },
                {
                    "question": "A bag contains 5 red balls and 7 green balls. If a ball is drawn at random, what is the probability of getting a green ball?",
                    "options": [
                        "a) 5/12",
                        "b) 7/12",
                        "c) 5/7",
                        "d) 7/5"
                    ],
                    "answer": "b) 7/12"
                },
                {
                    "question": "If the marked price of an article is Rs. 480 and after allowing a discount of 20%, it is sold for Rs. 384. What is the profit percentage?",
                    "options": [
                        "a) 20%",
                        "b) 25%",
                        "c) 30%",
                        "d) 35%"
                    ],
                    "answer": "c) 30%"
                },
                {
                    "question": "The sum of three consecutive odd numbers is 63. What is the largest of these numbers?",
                    "options": [
                        "a) 21",
                        "b) 23",
                        "c) 25",
                        "d) 27"
                    ],
                    "answer": "d) 27"
                },
                {
                    "question": "Statement: All cats are mammals. Conclusion: All mammals are cats. Is the conclusion true based on the statement?",
                    "options": [
                        "a) True",
                        "b) False",
                        "c) Cannot be determined"
                    ],
                    "answer": "b) False"
                },
                {
                    "question": "Arrange the given words in a meaningful sequence. River Ocean Sea Lake Choose the correct sequence:",
                    "options": [
                        "a) 1, 2, 3, 4",
                        "b) 2, 1, 3, 4",
                        "c) 2, 3, 1, 4",
                        "d) 3, 4, 1, 2"
                    ],
                    "answer": "c) 2, 3, 1, 4"
                },
                {
                    "question": "If TRAIN is coded as RTINA, how is CAUTION coded?",
                    "options": [
                        "a) UCATINO",
                        "b) UCNOTAI",
                        "c) UCOITNA",
                        "d) UCTIONA"
                    ],
                    "answer": "b) UCNOTAI"
                },
                {
                    "question": "If A = 1, B = 2, C = 3, ... Z = 26, then what is the value of HARD?",
                    "options": [
                        "a) 30",
                        "b) 28",
                        "c) 32",
                        "d) 34"
                    ],
                    "answer": "c) 32"
                },
                {
                    "question": "If the day after tomorrow is two days before Thursday, then what day is today?",
                    "options": [
                        "a) Monday",
                        "b) Tuesday",
                        "c) Wednesday",
                        "d) Thursday"
                    ],
                    "answer": "b) Tuesday"
                },
                {
                    "question": "If 5 + 3 = 28, 9 + 1 = 810, and 8 + 6 = 214, then 7 + 5 = ?",
                    "options": [
                        "a) 1112",
                        "b) 1230",
                        "c) 2121",
                        "d) 3124"
                    ],
                    "answer": "a) 1112"
                },
                {
                    "question": "If all roses are red and some red things are thorns, then:",
                    "options": [
                        "a) All roses are thorns.",
                        "b) Some roses are thorns.",
                        "c) Some thorns are roses.",
                        "d) None of the above."
                    ],
                    "answer": "b) Some roses are thorns."
                },
                {
                    "question": "If some stones are rocks and all rocks are mountains, then:",
                    "options": [
                        "a) All stones are mountains.",
                        "b) Some stones are mountains.",
                        "c) Some mountains are stones.",
                        "d) None of the above."
                    ],
                    "answer": "b) Some stones are mountains."
                },
                {
                    "question": "Find the odd one out:",
                    "options": [
                        "a) Square",
                        "b) Triangle",
                        "c) Circle",
                        "d) Rectangle"
                    ],
                    "answer": "c) Circle"
                },
                {
                    "question": "If the first two statements are true, is the last statement true? All players are winners. Some winners are champions. All players are champions.",
                    "options": [
                        "a) True",
                        "b) False",
                        "c) Cannot be determined"
                    ],
                    "answer": "a) True"
                },
                {
                    "question": "Which of the following materials is commonly used as a binding agent in concrete?",
                    "options": [
                        "a) Cement",
                        "b) Asphalt",
                        "c) Sand",
                        "d) Gravel"
                    ],
                    "answer": "a) Cement"
                },
                {
                    "question": "What does the term 'LEED' stand for in the context of sustainable building design?",
                    "options": [
                      "a) Local Environment and Energy Development",
                      "b) Leadership in Energy and Environmental Design",
                      "c) Land Engineering and Environmental Design",
                      "d) Low-Emission Energy Development"
                    ],
                    "answer": "b) Leadership in Energy and Environmental Design"
                },
                {
                  
                    "question": "Which of the following is NOT a primary function of a structural engineer?",
                    "options": [
                      "a) Designing foundations",
                      "b) Analyzing and designing structural systems",
                      "c) Managing construction projects",
                      "d) Ensuring structural safety and stability"
                    ],
                    "answer": "c) Managing construction projects"
                },
                {
                    "question": "What is the typical unit weight of water?",
                    "options": [
                      "a) 62.4 lb/ft^3",
                      "b) 1000 kg/m^3",
                      "c) 9.81 kN/m^3",
                      "d) 9800 N/m^3"
                    ],
                    "answer": "a) 62.4 lb/ft^3"
                },
                {
                    "question": "Which of the following Python functions correctly calculates the volume of a cylindrical tank given its radius and height?",
                    "options": [
                      "a) def calculate_cylinder_volume(r, h):\n    return math.pi * r ** 2 * h",
                      "b) def tank_volume(r, h):\n    return 2 * math.pi * r * h",
                      "c) def find_cylinder_volume(radius, height):\n    return math.pi * radius ** 2 * height",
                      "d) def volume(radius, height):\n    return math.pi * (radius ** 2) * height"
                    ],
                    "answer": "c) def find_cylinder_volume(radius, height):\n    return math.pi * radius ** 2 * height"
                },
                {
                    "question": "Which of the following types of soil has the smallest particle size?",
                    "options": [
                      "a) Gravel",
                      "b) Sand",
                      "c) Silt",
                      "d) Clay"
                    ],
                    "answer": "d) Clay"
                },
                {
                    "question": "What does the term 'BIM' stand for in the field of civil engineering?",
                    "options": [
                      "a) Building Information Modeling",
                      "b) Base Isolation Method",
                      "c) Bridge Inspection Management",
                      "d) Building Infrastructure Maintenance"
                    ],
                    "answer": "a) Building Information Modeling"
                },
                {
                    "question": "Which of the following tests is used to determine the consistency of concrete?",
                    "options": [
                      "a) Sieve analysis",
                      "b) Slump test",
                      "c) Proctor compaction test",
                      "d) Liquid limit test"
                    ],
                    "answer": "b) Slump test"
                },
                {
                    "type": "MCQ",
                    "question": "What is the purpose of a retaining wall in civil engineering?",
                    "options": [
                      "a) To support and stabilize slopes",
                      "b) To provide access to an elevated area",
                      "c) To filter stormwater runoff",
                      "d) To control traffic flow"
                    ],
                    "answer": "a) To support and stabilize slopes"
                },
                {
                    "type": "MCQ",
                    "question": "Which type of foundation is typically used for high-rise buildings?",
                    "options": [
                      "a) Shallow foundation",
                      "b) Mat foundation",
                      "c) Pile foundation",
                      "d) Raft foundation"
                    ],
                    "answer": "c) Pile foundation"
                }
            ]
        },
        {
            "title": "MECHANICAL ENGINEERING",
            "icon": "./assets/images/icon-js.svg",
            "questions": [
                {
                    "question": "In a class, there are 60 students, out of which 30 are girls. What is the ratio of boys to girls in the class?",
                    "options": [
                        "2:1",
                        "1:2",
                        "1:1",
                        "3:2"
                    ],
                    "answer": "1:1"
                },
                {
                    "question": "A train travels 400 km in 5 hours. What is its average speed in km/hr?",
                    "options": [
                        "75 km/hr",
                        "80 km/hr",
                        "85 km/hr",
                        "90 km/hr"
                    ],
                    "answer": "80 km/hr"
                },
                {
                    "question": "If the cost price of 20 articles is equal to the selling price of 25 articles, what is the profit percentage?",
                    "options": [
                        "20%",
                        "25%",
                        "30%",
                        "35%"
                    ],
                    "answer": "30%"               
                },
                { 
                    "question": "The perimeter of a rectangle is 40 cm and its length is twice its breadth. What is the area of the rectangle?",
                    "options": [
                        "a) 40 sq cm",
                        "b) 60 sq cm",
                        "c) 80 sq cm",
                        "d) 100 sq cm"
                   ],
                   "answer": "b) 60 sq cm"
                },
                {
                    "question": "If 15% of x is equal to 20% of y, and y = 200, what is the value of x?",
                    "options": [
                        "a) 150",
                        "b) 200",
                        "c) 250",
                        "d) 300"
                    ],
                    "answer": "a) 150"
                },
                {
                    "question": "A cube has a volume of 64 cubic meters. What is the length of its side?",
                    "options": [
                        "a) 4 meters",
                        "b) 6 meters",
                        "c) 8 meters",
                        "d) 10 meters"
                    ],
                    "answer": "b) 6 meters"
                },
                {
                    "question": "If the ratio of the circumference of two circles is 3:4, what is the ratio of their areas?",
                    "options": [
                        "a) 3:4",
                        "b) 9:16",
                        "c) 16:9",
                        "d) 27:64"
                    ],
                    "answer": "b) 9:16"
                },
                {
                    "question": "A bag contains 5 red balls and 7 green balls. If a ball is drawn at random, what is the probability of getting a green ball?",
                    "options": [
                        "a) 5/12",
                        "b) 7/12",
                        "c) 5/7",
                        "d) 7/5"
                    ],
                    "answer": "b) 7/12"
                },
                {
                    "question": "If the marked price of an article is Rs. 480 and after allowing a discount of 20%, it is sold for Rs. 384. What is the profit percentage?",
                    "options": [
                        "a) 20%",
                        "b) 25%",
                        "c) 30%",
                        "d) 35%"
                    ],
                    "answer": "c) 30%"
                },
                {
                    "question": "The sum of three consecutive odd numbers is 63. What is the largest of these numbers?",
                    "options": [
                        "a) 21",
                        "b) 23",
                        "c) 25",
                        "d) 27"
                    ],
                    "answer": "d) 27"
                },
                {
                    "question": "Statement: All cats are mammals. Conclusion: All mammals are cats. Is the conclusion true based on the statement?",
                    "options": [
                        "a) True",
                        "b) False",
                        "c) Cannot be determined"
                    ],
                    "answer": "b) False"
                },
                {
                    "question": "Arrange the given words in a meaningful sequence. River Ocean Sea Lake Choose the correct sequence:",
                    "options": [
                        "a) 1, 2, 3, 4",
                        "b) 2, 1, 3, 4",
                        "c) 2, 3, 1, 4",
                        "d) 3, 4, 1, 2"
                    ],
                    "answer": "c) 2, 3, 1, 4"
                },
                {
                    "question": "If TRAIN is coded as RTINA, how is CAUTION coded?",
                    "options": [
                        "a) UCATINO",
                        "b) UCNOTAI",
                        "c) UCOITNA",
                        "d) UCTIONA"
                    ],
                    "answer": "b) UCNOTAI"
                },
                {
                    "question": "If A = 1, B = 2, C = 3, ... Z = 26, then what is the value of HARD?",
                    "options": [
                        "a) 30",
                        "b) 28",
                        "c) 32",
                        "d) 34"
                    ],
                    "answer": "c) 32"
                },
                {
                    "question": "If the day after tomorrow is two days before Thursday, then what day is today?",
                    "options": [
                        "a) Monday",
                        "b) Tuesday",
                        "c) Wednesday",
                        "d) Thursday"
                    ],
                    "answer": "b) Tuesday"
                },
                {
                    "question": "If 5 + 3 = 28, 9 + 1 = 810, and 8 + 6 = 214, then 7 + 5 = ?",
                    "options": [
                        "a) 1112",
                        "b) 1230",
                        "c) 2121",
                        "d) 3124"
                    ],
                    "answer": "a) 1112"
                },
                {
                    "question": "If all roses are red and some red things are thorns, then:",
                    "options": [
                        "a) All roses are thorns.",
                        "b) Some roses are thorns.",
                        "c) Some thorns are roses.",
                        "d) None of the above."
                    ],
                    "answer": "b) Some roses are thorns."
                },
                {
                    "question": "If some stones are rocks and all rocks are mountains, then:",
                    "options": [
                        "a) All stones are mountains.",
                        "b) Some stones are mountains.",
                        "c) Some mountains are stones.",
                        "d) None of the above."
                    ],
                    "answer": "b) Some stones are mountains."
                },
                {
                    "question": "Find the odd one out:",
                    "options": [
                        "a) Square",
                        "b) Triangle",
                        "c) Circle",
                        "d) Rectangle"
                    ],
                    "answer": "c) Circle"
                },
                {
                    "question": "If the first two statements are true, is the last statement true? All players are winners. Some winners are champions. All players are champions.",
                    "options": [
                        "a) True",
                        "b) False",
                        "c) Cannot be determined"
                    ],
                    "answer": "a) True"
                },
                {
                    "question": "Which of the following thermodynamic processes occurs at constant volume?",
                    "options": [
                      "a) Isothermal",
                      "b) Adiabatic",
                      "c) Isobaric",
                      "d) Isochoric"
                    ],
                    "answer": "d) Isochoric"
                },
                {
                    "question": "Which type of heat transfer relies on the movement of fluid?",
                    "options": [
                      "a) Conduction",
                      "b) Convection",
                      "c) Radiation",
                      "d) Absorption"
                    ],
                    "answer": "b) Convection"
                },
                {
                    "question": "What does the term 'CNC' stand for in manufacturing?",
                    "options": [
                      "a) Computer Numerical Control",
                      "b) Centralized Numeric Control",
                      "c) Control Network Coordination",
                      "d) Computerized Nanotechnology Control"
                    ],
                    "answer": "a) Computer Numerical Control"
                },
                {
                    "question": "Which of the following materials has the highest Young's modulus?",
                    "options": [
                      "a) Rubber",
                      "b) Steel",
                      "c) Aluminum",
                      "d) Copper"
                    ],
                    "answer": "b) Steel"
                },
                {
                    "question": "Which of the following thermodynamic cycles is used in gas turbines?",
                    "options": [
                      "a) Rankine cycle",
                      "b) Carnot cycle",
                      "c) Otto cycle",
                      "d) Brayton cycle"
                    ],
                    "answer": "d) Brayton cycle"
                },
                {
                    "question": "What is the primary purpose of a flywheel in a machine?",
                    "options": [
                      "a) To store electrical energy",
                      "b) To maintain a constant rotational speed",
                      "c) To convert rotary motion into linear motion",
                      "d) To amplify force"
                    ],
                    "answer": "b) To maintain a constant rotational speed"
                },
                {
                    "question": "Which material is commonly used as a lubricant in mechanical systems?",
                    "options": [
                      "a) Graphite",
                      "b) Silicone",
                      "c) Teflon",
                      "d) PVC"
                    ],
                    "answer": "a) Graphite"
                },
                {
                    "question": "What is the SI unit of pressure?",
                    "options": [
                      "a) Pascal",
                      "b) Newton",
                      "c) Joule",
                      "d) Watt"
                    ],
                    "answer": "a) Pascal"
                }
                
            ]
        },
        {
            "title": "EC/EE ENGINEERING",
            "icon": "./assets/images/icon-accessibility.svg",
            "questions": [
                {
                    "question": "In a class, there are 60 students, out of which 30 are girls. What is the ratio of boys to girls in the class?",
                    "options": [
                        "2:1",
                        "1:2",
                        "1:1",
                        "3:2"
                    ],
                    "answer": "1:1"
                },
                {
                    "question": "A train travels 400 km in 5 hours. What is its average speed in km/hr?",
                    "options": [
                        "75 km/hr",
                        "80 km/hr",
                        "85 km/hr",
                        "90 km/hr"
                    ],
                    "answer": "80 km/hr"
                },
                {
                    "question": "If the cost price of 20 articles is equal to the selling price of 25 articles, what is the profit percentage?",
                    "options": [
                        "20%",
                        "25%",
                        "30%",
                        "35%"
                    ],
                    "answer": "30%"
                },
                {
                    "question": "The perimeter of a rectangle is 40 cm and its length is twice its breadth. What is the area of the rectangle?",
                    "options": [
                         "a) 40 sq cm",
                         "b) 60 sq cm",
                         "c) 80 sq cm",
                         "d) 100 sq cm"
                    ],
                    "answer": "b) 60 sq cm"        },
                {
                    "question": "If 15% of x is equal to 20% of y, and y = 200, what is the value of x?",
                    "options": [
                        "a) 150",
                        "b) 200",
                        "c) 250",
                        "d) 300"
                    ],
                    "answer": "a) 150"
                },
                {
                    "question": "A cube has a volume of 64 cubic meters. What is the length of its side?",
                    "options": [
                        "a) 4 meters",
                        "b) 6 meters",
                        "c) 8 meters",
                        "d) 10 meters"
                    ],
                    "answer": "b) 6 meters"
                },
                {
                    "question": "If the ratio of the circumference of two circles is 3:4, what is the ratio of their areas?",
                    "options": [
                        "a) 3:4",
                        "b) 9:16",
                        "c) 16:9",
                        "d) 27:64"
                    ],
                    "answer": "b) 9:16"
                },
                {
                    "question": "A bag contains 5 red balls and 7 green balls. If a ball is drawn at random, what is the probability of getting a green ball?",
                    "options": [
                        "a) 5/12",
                        "b) 7/12",
                        "c) 5/7",
                        "d) 7/5"
                    ],
                    "answer": "b) 7/12"
                },
                {
                    "question": "If the marked price of an article is Rs. 480 and after allowing a discount of 20%, it is sold for Rs. 384. What is the profit percentage?",
                    "options": [
                        "a) 20%",
                        "b) 25%",
                        "c) 30%",
                        "d) 35%"
                    ],
                    "answer": "c) 30%"
                },
                {
                    "question": "The sum of three consecutive odd numbers is 63. What is the largest of these numbers?",
                    "options": [
                        "a) 21",
                        "b) 23",
                        "c) 25",
                        "d) 27"
                    ],
                    "answer": "d) 27"
                },
                {
                    "question": "Statement: All cats are mammals. Conclusion: All mammals are cats. Is the conclusion true based on the statement?",
                    "options": [
                        "a) True",
                        "b) False",
                        "c) Cannot be determined"
                    ],
                    "answer": "b) False"
                },
                {
                    "question": "Arrange the given words in a meaningful sequence. River Ocean Sea Lake Choose the correct sequence:",
                    "options": [
                        "a) 1, 2, 3, 4",
                        "b) 2, 1, 3, 4",
                        "c) 2, 3, 1, 4",
                        "d) 3, 4, 1, 2"
                    ],
                    "answer": "c) 2, 3, 1, 4"
                },
                {
                    "question": "If TRAIN is coded as RTINA, how is CAUTION coded?",
                    "options": [
                        "a) UCATINO",
                        "b) UCNOTAI",
                        "c) UCOITNA",
                        "d) UCTIONA"
                    ],
                    "answer": "b) UCNOTAI"
                },
                {
                    "question": "If A = 1, B = 2, C = 3, ... Z = 26, then what is the value of HARD?",
                    "options": [
                        "a) 30",
                        "b) 28",
                        "c) 32",
                        "d) 34"
                    ],
                    "answer": "c) 32"
                },
                {
                    "question": "If the day after tomorrow is two days before Thursday, then what day is today?",
                    "options": [
                        "a) Monday",
                        "b) Tuesday",
                        "c) Wednesday",
                        "d) Thursday"
                    ],
                    "answer": "b) Tuesday"
                },
                {
                    "question": "If 5 + 3 = 28, 9 + 1 = 810, and 8 + 6 = 214, then 7 + 5 = ?",
                    "options": [
                        "a) 1112",
                        "b) 1230",
                        "c) 2121",
                        "d) 3124"
                    ],
                    "answer": "a) 1112"
                },
                {
                    "question": "If all roses are red and some red things are thorns, then:",
                    "options": [
                        "a) All roses are thorns.",
                        "b) Some roses are thorns.",
                        "c) Some thorns are roses.",
                        "d) None of the above."
                    ],
                    "answer": "b) Some roses are thorns."
                },
                {
                    "question": "If some stones are rocks and all rocks are mountains, then:",
                    "options": [
                        "a) All stones are mountains.",
                        "b) Some stones are mountains.",
                        "c) Some mountains are stones.",
                        "d) None of the above."
                    ],
                    "answer": "b) Some stones are mountains."
                },
                {
                    "question": "Find the odd one out:",
                    "options": [
                        "a) Square",
                        "b) Triangle",
                        "c) Circle",
                        "d) Rectangle"
                    ],
                    "answer": "c) Circle"
                },
                {
                    "question": "If the first two statements are true, is the last statement true? All players are winners. Some winners are champions. All players are champions.",
                    "options": [
                        "a) True",
                        "b) False",
                        "c) Cannot be determined"
                    ],
                    "answer": "a) True"
                },
                {
                    "question": "What does the term 'AC' stand for in electrical engineering?",
                    "options": [
                      "a) Alternating Current",
                      "b) Amplified Current",
                      "c) Attenuated Current",
                      "d) Analog Current"
                    ],
                    "answer": "a) Alternating Current"
                },
                {
                    "question": "Which semiconductor device is primarily used for rectification in power supply circuits?",
                    "options": [
                      "a) Transistor",
                      "b) Diode",
                      "c) Thyristor",
                      "d) MOSFET"
                    ],
                    "answer": "b) Diode"
                },
                {
                    "question": "What is the SI unit of electric charge?",
                    "options": [
                      "a) Ampere",
                      "b) Volt",
                      "c) Coulomb",
                      "d) Ohm"
                    ],
                    "answer": "c) Coulomb"
                },
                {
                    "question": "Which of the following devices converts electrical energy into mechanical energy?",
                    "options": [
                      "a) Transformer",
                      "b) Inductor",
                      "c) Capacitor",
                      "d) Electric Motor"
                    ],
                    "answer": "d) Electric Motor"
                },
                {
                    "question": "What is the primary function of an operational amplifier (op-amp) in electronic circuits?",
                    "options": [
                      "a) Signal amplification",
                      "b) Signal rectification",
                      "c) Signal modulation",
                      "d) Signal generation"
                    ],
                    "answer": "a) Signal amplification"
                },
                {
                    "question": "Which of the following is NOT a type of logic gate?",
                    "options": [
                      "a) AND gate",
                      "b) OR gate",
                      "c) XOR gate",
                      "d) Amplifier gate"
                    ],
                    "answer": "d) Amplifier gate"
                },
                {
                    "question": "Which semiconductor device is used for voltage regulation in electronic circuits?",
                    "options": [
                      "a) Transistor",
                      "b) Diode",
                      "c) Zener diode",
                      "d) Thyristor"
                    ],
                    "answer": "c) Zener diode"
                },
                {
                    "question": "What is the primary function of a capacitor in electronic circuits?",
                    "options": [
                      "a) Voltage amplification",
                      "b) Current rectification",
                      "c) Energy storage",
                      "d) Signal generation"
                    ],
                    "answer": "c) Energy storage"
                },
                {
                    "question": "What is the SI unit of frequency?",
                    "options": [
                      "a) Hertz",
                      "b) Watt",
                      "c) Ohm",
                      "d) Farad"
                    ],
                    "answer": "a) Hertz"
                }
            ]
        }
    ]
}